# **ZACHARY SWOGGER**

New Holland, PA (717)-380-1381

## **Professional Summary**

Aspiring software engineer with a drive to quickly and effectively learn new technologies and implement them correctly into my work. With 9 years of experience in IT ranging from helpdesk support to managing all IT matters for an entire school, I am ready to take the next step and begin my career as a software engineer.

You may find some of my personal projects here: www.Github.com/zswogger

## Skills

- C# .NET
- Java
- SQL
- HTML
- CSS

- ASP.NET
- OOP
- Microsoft SQL Server
- MVC
- Agile

## Work History

## **Desktop Support Technician**

6/2021 to Current

Linden Hall School for Girls

- Kept costs below operating budget by properly maintaining current systems
- Advise Head of School on all IT related matters
- Coordinate with MSP for network related matters
- Ensure quality and timely service to all faculty, staff, and students
- Developed new software used within the school

## Helpdesk Technician 6/2019 to 6/2021

#### County of Lancaster

- Broke down and evaluated user problems, using personal expertise and probing questions.
- Configured hardware, devices, and software to ensure employee success.
- Onboard new employees and their devices.
- Perform follow ups to confirm customer satisfaction.

## System Administrator

5/2013 to 12/2018

#### **US** Army

- Configured, tested, and maintained garrison and tactical network equipment to achieve mission success.
- Removed malware, ransomware and other threats from laptops and desktop systems.
- Configured hardware, devices, and software to set up workstations for employees.

#### Education

# **Bachelor of Science:** Software Development Expected in 5/2023

Grand Canyon University